Michael Martinez

Beaumont, CA 92223 | 951-722-5758 | michael.martinez2707@gmail.com Linkedin| blog | github

Software Engineer

With a background in biological sciences, I bring strong analytical skills to tech projects with a desire to create an impact. After experimenting with programming class in college, I discovered that I had a passion for software development. After some self-led learning, I decided to make the leap and join Flatiron School's bootcamp to jumpstart my career. Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in React with Redux. Possess strong skills in team-building and project management that help drive teamwork and increase client satisfaction. Passionate about learning new things and staying current with the technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

WebMart - github| demo

A mock e-commerce app allowing users to add/search for items

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Fetched seeded images from a cloud-based storage.
- Allowed for adding/removing items to/from a user's shopping cart.
- Used hooks to access app lifecycle.

AnimeList - Github | Demo

Brief description of the app's functionality and purpose.

- Communicated with AnimeAPI endpoints to render real-time information.
- Allowed the user to store anime information to lists and to edit these lists.

Mama Bear - Github | Demo

Ecommerce site for a non profit organization allowing for the tracking and selling of used clothing.

- Engineered user interface with javascript for a responsive user experience.
- Developed a postgres database with a user friendly access to edit and add information.

EXPERIENCE

Lowe's Redlands, CA 11/2020 - Present Pro Sales Specialist

- Worked with 3rd party vendors to place and plan product orders and deliveries.
- Assisted customers with Lowe's account and credit card sign-ups.
- Increased department sales profits by 13% in my first three months

Home Depot San Bernardino, CA 01/2016 - 11/2020

Pro Account Sales Associate

- Assisted contractors with sales over the phone and in person.
- Coordinated with other departments to fulfil customer orders.
- Reduced losses due to lost product from disorganized orders by 8%

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Brooklyn, NY Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 10/ 2020 - 08/2021

University of Redlands Redlands, CA Bachelor of Arts in Biology 01/2012 - 04/2014